outskirtspress.com 2009-06-08

# Outskirts Press - Privacy Policy

This privacy pledge discloses how Outskirts Press, Inc. handles personal information collected by Outskirts Press, including personal information related to your publication. Any user of the Outskirts Press website hereby verifies that they are 13 years of age or older.

Personal information is information like your name, address, email address, or phone number, as well as additional information that is not otherwise publicly available.

Outskirts Press may collect personal information when you register for an Author's Center, when you click on a Pay-per-Click ad paid for by Outskirts Press, or when you participate in the publishing process through the Outskirts Press website. 

Outskirts Press collects information about your transactions with us through your use of the services that we offer. We do not purchase any personal data from other companies. 

Our website host automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, browser settings, and pages requested. Outskirts Press also writes a cookie to your computer. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer. Outskirts Press will write and access Outskirts Press cookies on your computer to facilitate your log-in process or to track your affiliate referrals. The information linked by the cookie is only your user ID number. We do not link to or store any other personally identifiable information to the cookie. We use both session ID cookies (for the shopping cart) and persistent cookies (for the Author's Center and Affiliate program). You can manually delete cookies at any time by following the directions given in your Internet browser’s Help file. 

Outskirts Press uses personal information to:

  * fulfill your requests for products and services 
  * contact you 
  * offer author support either via the Author Services (pre-publication) support program or the Marketing COACH (post-publication) support program. As a registered participant of this program, Outskirts Press may send e-mails containing publishing or promotion information geared toward helping you make decisions regarding publication and marketing. 

In order to publish through Outskirts Press, you will need to create an Author account. When you register for an account, we will ask for your first name and email address. This is the only required information prior to becoming a paying customer of Outskirts Press, although optional personal information includes your last name, mailing address, and phone number. Once you register for an Author's Center account, you are not anonymous to us. Registering for an Author's Center automatically qualifies you for the Author Services support program. You can edit your account information at any time, including changing or removing your last name, address, phone number. You may also change or edit your email address or password at any time. 

You also have the opportunity to opt-in to receive email newsletters. Our email newsletter database is compiled separately and independently from our database of registered users, and is stored by a 3rd party vendor, Bravenet. The only information Bravenet receives through this form is your email address, which they are not authorized to use for any purpose other than sending you the Outskirts Press newsletter. Prior to your receipt of the first newsletter you must complete a double-opt-in procedure, verifying your email address. At any time you may opt out of receiving the Outskirts Press newsletter, the Author Services support and/or the Marketing COACH support.

When you begin the publishing process with your deposit or full package fee, we will ask for your full name, billing address, and phone number. We will also ask for payment information (credit card number) and your billing address. This information is securely processed through Thawte secure certification and is encrypted through secure socket layer (SSL) technology for your protection.

We never keep your credit card information on file or stored online. Every time you purchase, you will need to re-enter your credit card number. This is for your protection and security. Additionally, when you order books, we will request your delivery address for the purposes of calculating your shipping fees and for the purposes of delivering your order.

In order to receive royalty checks, you will have to maintain an accurate postal address in your author's center, including your full name name, address, and phone number.

Your royalties may be subject to US tax laws. Therefore, in order to receive payment, you will need to provide either your SSN, TIN, or EIN for the sole purpose of our issuing a 1099 form reporting your annual earnings.

If you are not a US taxpayer, you will be required to complete a W8 form declaring your exemption. 

We limit employee and contractor access to your personal information. For example, only the accounting department has access to your tax information. 

If you include any personal information in content that you save to your author webpage or include in your book, that information may be widely available to other users. Outskirts Press does not exercise control over those users and cannot guarantee that your personal information will be protected as described in this Privacy Policy. Outskirts Press does not delete or edit your personal information from any content you provide. If you do not want your personal information to be displayed, then only include it in the Author Profile section of your author's center.

Outside of what is described above, Outskirts Press does not share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies, although we may need to disclose your personal information in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or as otherwise required by law. Additionally, we may need to disclose your personal information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or violations of our production and distribution agreement. Lastly, we would need to share your personal information in the event Outskirts Press is acquired by or merged with another company.

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information. 

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Outskirts Press, Inc. does not own or control, nor to people that Outskirts Press does not employ.
